- 这是最大放大倍数吗，上尉？  - 是的，长官
- Is this full magnification, Lieutenant? - Yes, sir.
- 导弹详情，史波克先生？  - 古老的类型，亚光速
- Missile spread, Mr. Spock? - Archaic type. Sublight speed.
是的，用化学燃料推进
Aye, and chemically fueled to boot.
- 有任何通讯吗？  - 没有，长官
- Anything on communication? - No, sir.
- 导弹航向，史波克先生？  - 目标是企业号
- Course of the missile, Mr. Spock? - The Enterprise is the target.
准备相1号和2号位炮台，苏鲁先生
Prepare phaser banks one and two, Mr. Sulu.
契科夫先生，确定导弹的发射点
Mr. Chekov, get a fix on the missile's point of origin.
1号和2号相位炮台已锁定并准备好，长官
Phasers one and two locked in and ready, sir.
发射相位炮
Fire phasers.
契科夫先生，改变航线到导弹的原点
Mr. Chekov, alter course to the missile's point of origin.
- 曲速3，苏鲁先生  - 是的，长官
- Warp factor 3, Mr. Sulu. - Yes, sir.
我首先是一名护士，麦考伊医生，然后是一名船员
I am a nurse first, Dr. McCoy, and a member of the crew second.
你被解除职务了，去你的宿舍
You're excused. Go to your quarters.
抱歉，我已经呼叫舰长了，我会等他来
I'm sorry. I've called the captain and I'll wait until he comes.
- 有什么急事？  - 我说你被解除职务了，护士
- What's the emergency? - I said you were excused, Nurse.
拜托，克里斯汀，我向你保证我会给舰长一份完整的报告
Please, Christine. I promise you I'll give the captain a full report.
那场面真壮观
That was quite a scene.
我已经完成了船员的身体检查
I've completed physical examinations for the crew.
- 有什么紧急情况？  - 船员身体健康
- What's the emergency? - The crew is fit.
我没有发现任何异常，只有一个例外
I found nothing unusual, with one exception.
- 严重吗？  - 已经是晚期了
- Serious? - Terminal.
- 什么病？  - 异种红细胞增多症，它无法治愈
- What is it? - Xenopolycythemia. It has no cure.
- 谁？  - 他最多只能活一年
- Who? - He has one year to live at the most.
- 是谁？  - 船上的首席医疗官
- Who is it? - The ship's chief medical officer.
- 你？  - 如果你保守这个秘密
- You? - I'll be most effective on the job
我才能好好工作
if you'll keep this to yourself.
柯克：宇宙，最后的边疆
KIRK: Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
柯克：舰长日志，星历5476.3
KIRK: Captain's log, stardate 5476.3.
我已将麦考伊医生的病情告知星际舰队
I have informed Starfleet about Dr. McCoy's condition
并要求立即更换人员
and have requested an immediate replacement.
- 史波克先生  - 是的，舰长？
- Mr. Spock. - Yes, Captain?
确认导弹原点的坐标
Confirm coordinates for the missile's origin.
正确，我们正在接近这些坐标
Correct. We are approaching those coordinates.
- 屏幕上的那个物体？  - 一颗直径为200英里的小行星
- That object on the screen? - An asteroid, 200 miles in diameter.
敌舰会躲在它后面吗？
Could the enemy vessel be hiding behind it?
不会，舰长，我们一直在扫描这个区域
Negative, Captain. We've had that area on scanners constantly.
那么小行星是导弹的原点吗？
Then the asteroid is the missile's point of origin?
是的，舰长
Correct, Captain.
用全部传感器进行探测，史波克先生
Full sensor probe, Mr. Spock.
典型的小行星化学组成，但它不绕轨道运行
Typical asteroid chemically, but it is not orbiting.
它沿着一条穿过太阳系的独立路线
It is pursuing an independent course through this solar system.
怎么会这样？
How could that be?
除非它是…有动力的，一艘太空飞船？
Unless it's... powered. A spaceship?
它是有动力的，舰长
It is under power, Captain.
- 动力源？  - 核动力，非常古老
- Power source? - Atomic, very archaic.
留下一串碎片和硬辐射
Leaving a trail of debris and hard radiation.
契科夫先生，绘制小行星飞船的路线图
Mr. Chekov, plot the course of the asteroid vessel.
小行星有一个外壳，是空心的
Asteroid has an outer shell, which is hollow.
它包含着一个独立的内核，由可呼吸的大气
It surrounds an independent core, which has a breathable atmosphere.
- 传感器没有探测到生命形式  - 它一定处于自动控制状态
- Sensors read no life-forms. - It must be on automatic controls.
乘客或建造者死了
The passengers or builders are dead.
小行星的航向，我是说，飞船的航向，241，标记17
Course of asteroid, I mean, spaceship, 241, mark 17.
- 真有趣  - 是的
- Interesting. - Yes.
那个航向将使小行星与达兰五号发生碰撞
That course would put the asteroid on a collision course with Daran V.
- 达兰五号？有人居住吗？  - 是的
- Daran V? Inhabited? - Correct.
人口大约37.24亿，如果我没记错的话
Population approximately three billion, 724 million, if my memory is correct.
预计冲撞时间，396天
Estimated time of impact, 396 days.
苏鲁先生，调整企业号速度与小行星飞船相同
Mr. Sulu. Match Enterprise speed with that of the asteroid vessel.
史波克先生和我要传送登船，斯科特先生，指挥操舵
Mr. Spock and I are transporting aboard. Mr. Scott, you have the conn.
一年可以发生很多事情，请珍惜每一分钟
A lot can happen in a year. Please, give yourself every minute.
麦考伊医生，史波克先生和我会处理这件事
Dr. McCoy, Mr. Spock and I will handle this.
不带上我，吉姆？你会连回来的路都找不到
Without me, Jim? You'd never find your way back.
呃…
Well...
- 我认为更明智的做法是…  - 我想去，我很好，舰长
- I think it would be wiser if... - I'd like to go. I'm fine, Captain.
好的，医生，如果那是你想要的
All right, Doctor. If that's what you want.
麦考伊：我发誓我在一颗行星上
McCOY: You'd swear you were on a planet.
史波克：造一艘看起来像行星的船的逻辑是什么？
SPOCK: What is the logic in making a ship look like a planet?
真看不出这是艘太空飞船，柯克呼叫企业号
Wouldn't know this was a spaceship. Kirk to Enterprise.
- 企业号，我是斯科特  - 安全到达，完毕
- Enterprise, Scott here. - Transported without incident. Out.
没有可见的入口
No apparent opening.
你没有发现智能生命形式，但肯定…
You've found no intelligent life-forms, but surely...
这艘船已经有10,000多年的历史了，医生
The ship is over 10,000 years old, Doctor.
仍然没有生命形式的迹象，舰长
Still no sign of life-forms, Captain.
这些是武器？
These are weapons?
算是一种，武器，通讯设备
Of a sort. Weapons, communication devices.
让我去找我的朋友
Let me go to my friend.
- 你没事吧？  - 我没事
- You all right? - I think so.
我是纳提拉，人民的高级女祭司
I am Natira, the high priestess of the people.
欢迎来到尤纳达的世界
Welcome to the world of Yonada.
我得说这可不算什么欢迎
I can't say I think much of your welcome.
带他们走
Take them.
你们要跪下
You will kneel.
她称这个为“世界”，这些人不知道他们在船上
She called this "the world". These people don't know they're on a ship.
它们已经飞行了10,000年，也许他们没有意识到
They've been in flight 10,000 years. Maybe they don't realize it.
哦，人民的神谕，最完美和最明智的
Oh, Oracle of the people, most perfect and wise.
陌生人来到了我们的世界
Strangers have come to our world.
他们带着我们不懂的器械
They bear instruments we do not understand.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是星舰企业号的柯克舰长
I am Captain Kirk of the starship Enterprise.
这是我的医疗官，麦考伊医生，我的大副，史波克先生
This is my medical officer, Dr. McCoy. My first officer, Mr. Spock.
- 你为什么要来到这个世界？  - 我们是出于友谊而来的
- Why do you visit this world? - We've come in friendship.
[雷声]
[THUNDER CRACK]
神谕：了解成为我们的敌人意味着什么
ORACLE: Learn what it means to be our enemy
在你了解成为我们的朋友意味着什么之前
before you learn what it means to be our friend.
史波克
Spock.
麦考伊医生，老骨头
Dr. McCoy. Bones.
老骨头？
Bones?
医生一定是受到了过度的电击
The doctor must have received an excessive shock.
不，不是这样
No, that's not it.
没有其他原因可以造成这种情况，舰长
Nothing else could have caused this, Captain.
至少，这里没有发生过什么
At least, nothing that has happened here.
你说得对，由于麦考伊的虚弱状况，电击很严重
You're right. The shock was serious due to McCoy's weakened condition.
请问医生究竟有什么问题？
May I ask precisely what is troubling the doctor?
我认为他不会告诉你，但我认为你现在应该知道了
I don't think he would have told you, but I think you should know now.
是异种红细胞增多症
It's xenopolycythemia.
好吧，我知道这个，舰长
Yes. I know of it, Captain.
那你就知道它是绝症
Then you know that nothing can be done.
老骨头，怎么样？
Bones, how is it?
我很好
I'm all right.
- 你还好吗，史波克先生？  - 很好，医生
- Are you all right, Mr. Spock? - Very well, Doctor.
舰长和我似乎没有受到任何不良影响
The captain and I seem to have suffered no ill effects.
那个“神谕”真的吓到我了
That "Oracle" really got to me.
我一定对它的魔咒特别敏感
I must be especially susceptible to its magic spells.
史波克知道了
Spock knows.
好吧，我们最好去控制室
Well, we better get to the control room.
- 你可以起来吗？  - 别担心，我能做到，吉姆
- Are you in any condition to get up? - Don't worry, I can make it, Jim.
告知这些人他们在船上
Informing these people they're on a ship
可能违反星际舰队的最高指令
may violate Starfleet's Prime Directive.
不，尤纳达的人民可能会因知识而改变
No, the people of Yonada may be changed by the knowledge,
但总比消灭它们好
but it's better than exterminating them.
- 合乎逻辑，舰长  - 还有达兰五号上的30亿人
- Logical, Captain. - And the three billion on Daran V.
也是合乎逻辑的，舰长
Also logical, Captain.
先生们，我想我们有个客人
Gentlemen, I believe we have a visitor.
能增强力量
For strength.
我们中的许多人都感受到了我们神谕的力量
Many of us have felt the power of our oracle.
这很有用
This has been of benefit.
尝起来像一种古代的草药制品
Tastes like an ancient herb derivative.
- 你不是尤纳达人  - 不，我们来自你的世界之外
- You are not of Yonada. - No, we're from outside your world.
哪里…是外面？
Where... is outside?
上面
Up there.
外面，上面，到处
Outside, up there, everywhere.
他们也这么说
So they say, also.
很多年前
Many years ago,
我爬上了山，尽管这是被禁止的
I climbed the mountains, even though it is forbidden.
为什么被禁止？
Why is it forbidden?
我不知道
I am not sure.
但事情并非…
But things are not...
他们教我们的那样
as they teach us.
因为世界是空心的
For the world is hollow,
而我触碰到了天空
and I have touched the sky.
- 这是什么，老骨头？  - 皮肤下有东西
- What is it, Bones? - There's something under the skin.
他死了
He's dead.
“因为世界是空心的，而我触碰到了天空”
"For the world is hollow and I have touched the sky."
- 禁止爬山  - 当然
- It's forbidden to climb the mountains. - Of course.
因为如果你这样做了，你会发现你生活在一个大球上
Because if you did, you'd find out you were living on a big ball.
不是一颗行星而是一艘宇宙飞船，而这种知识似乎是被禁止的
Not a planet but a spaceship. And that knowledge seems to be forbidden.
发生了什么？
What happened?
我们不知道，他痛苦地尖叫着死去了
We don't know. He screamed in pain and died.
叫守卫来
Fetch the guard.
原谅他，因为他是个老人
Forgive him, for he was an old man.
而老人有时是愚蠢的
And old men are sometimes foolish.
但书上说，那些犯罪或说坏话的人
But it is written that those of the people who sin or speak evil
将受到惩罚
shall be punished.
多年来他认真工作
He served well for many years.
把他带走，轻轻地
Take him away, gently.
你看起来不太好，这让我很难受
You do not seem well. It is distressing to me.
我很好，谢谢
I'm quite all right, thank you.
您现在被视为贵宾，这是神谕的意愿
It is the will of the Oracle that you now be treated as honored guests.
你似乎受到特别的喜爱
You seem to be the special favorite.
这位年轻女士确实很喜欢你的陪伴
The young lady did show a preference for your company.
- 没有人可以为此责怪她  - 我觉得她的品味值得怀疑
- Nobody can blame her for that. - I find her taste questionable.
但她显然更喜欢你，而你似乎并不介意
But she obviously prefers you and you obviously don't seem to mind.
如果你能安排和那位小姐单独相处
If you could arrange to be alone with the young lady,
史波克和我可以找到这个…世界的能量控制器
Spock and I could find the power controls of this... world.
是时候让自己焕然一新了
It is time to refresh yourselves.
谢谢你，史波克先生
Thank you, Mr. Spock.
敬我们尤纳达的好朋友
To our good friends of Yonada.
- 我们对你们的世界很感兴趣  - 这让我们高兴
- We are very interested in your world. - That pleases us.
你介意我们到处看看吗？
You mind if we looked around?
一点也不，人民现在认识你们了
Not at all. The people know of you now.
[咳嗽]
[COUGHS]
你可以走动吗？
Are you well enough to go about?
也许不行
Perhaps not.
那为什么不留在这里呢？休息一下，我们聊聊天
Then why not remain here? Rest, we will talk.
你真体贴
You are very kind.
你们可以自由地四处走动并见见我们的人民
You are free to go about and meet our people.
谢谢
Thank you.
感谢你照顾麦考伊医生
And thank you for taking care of Dr. McCoy.
不用谢，我们会让他好起来的
Not at all. We shall make him well.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
不，谢谢
No, thank you.
请离开吧
Leave us.
我很好奇，神谕是如何惩罚那位老人的？
I'm curious. How did the Oracle punish the old man?
我…
I...
…现在不能告诉你
...cannot tell you now.
神谕有办法知道你说了什么，不是吗？
There is some way the Oracle knows what you say, isn't there?
我们说的，我们想的
What we say, what we think.
神谕知道所有人的想法和内心
The Oracle knows the minds and the hearts of all the people.
我不知道你会受到如此严重的伤害
I did not know you would be hurt so badly.
没关系
It's all right.
我想我们必须学习神谕的力量
I suppose we had to learn the power of the Oracle.
有件事我必须说，自从我…
There is something I must say. Since the moment I...
隐藏自己的感情不符合人民的方式
It is not in the manner of the people to hide their feelings.
诚实是…通常是明智的
Honesty is... usually wise.
你有女人吗？
Is there a woman for you?
不，没有
No, there isn't.
麦考伊觉得我有吸引力吗？
Does McCoy find me attractive?
哦，是的，是的，你有
Oh, yes. Yes, I do.
我希望你们来自太空的
I hope you men of space,
来自其他世界的人
of other worlds,
像我们一样珍视真理
hold truth as dear as we do.
我们的确是
We do.
我希望你留在这里，在尤纳达
I wish you to stay here, on Yonada,
作为我的伴侣
as my mate.
但我们彼此还是陌生人
But we're strangers to each other.
但这不正是人的天性吗？
But is not that the nature of men and women?
乐趣不就是互相了解的过程吗？
That the pleasure is in the learning of each other?
是的
Yes.
让思想在你心中安息
Let the thought rest in your heart.
这些人不知道他们生活在宇宙飞船上
These people have no idea they're living on a spaceship.
多少代人度过了他们的一生
How many generations have lived out their lives,
并被埋葬在这里
and been buried here,
但不知道他们的世界其实是空心的？
without ever knowing their world is hollow?
人民，在充实的时间里，
The people, in the fullness of time,
将到达一个新的世界
will reach a new world.
富饶，充满生机，赏心悦目
Rich, green, lovely to the eyes,
以及善良
and of a goodness
将使人们的心中充满喜悦的泪水。
that will fill the hearts of the people with tears of joy.
你我一起分享那个世界
You can share that world with me,
一起统治它
rule it by my side.
你需要多久才能到达这个新世界？
How long will it take you to reach this new world?
很快，神谕只会说“很快”
Soon. The Oracle will only say "soon".
要是你知道我多么需要某种未来就好了，纳提拉
If you only knew how I needed some kind of future, Natira.
你过着孤独的生活吗？
You have lived a lonely life?
是的，很孤独
Yes, very lonely.
不会了，麦考伊
No more, McCoy.
你将不再孤独
There will be no more loneliness for you.
- 有件事我需要告诉你  - 不要说
- There's something I need to tell you. - There's not.
- 但必须说  - 那就告诉我吧
- But there is. - Then tell me.
如果你真的要说
If the telling is such a need.
我得了一种绝症
I have an illness for which there is no cure.
我还有一年的寿命
I have one year to live.
遇见你之前，我的心是一片空白
Until I saw you, there was nothing in my heart.
它维持着我的生命，但仅此而已
It sustained my life, but nothing more.
现在它会唱歌
Now it sings.
我很高兴有这种感觉，哪怕一天
I could be happy to have that feeling for a day
一个星期，一个月…
a week, a month...
…一年
...a year.
无论创造者为我们安排了什么
Whatever the creators hold in store for us.
舰长，神谕室
Captain, the Oracle room.
问题：进入
The problem: to get in.
我相信我可以…
I believe that I can...
这些字绝对是法布里尼语，我认得
The writing is definitely Fabrini. I recognize it.
法布里尼的太阳不是变成了新星并摧毁了它的行星吗？
Didn't the Fabrini sun go nova and destroy its planets?
到最后，法布里尼人住在地下
Towards the end, the Fabrini people lived underground
来保护自己
to protect themselves.
他们中的一些人肯定已经被安置在这艘船上
Some of them must have been put aboard this ship.
而这些都是他们的后代
And these are their descendants.
现在
Now.
神谕似乎不知道我们在这里
The Oracle doesn't seem to know we're here.
- 我想知道第一次是什么提醒了它  - 舰长…
- I wonder what alerted it the first time. - Captain...
当纳提拉跪在那里时，神谕不友好的行为就开始了
The Oracle's reprehensible conduct was initiated when Natira knelt there.
我觉得你是对的，继续调查
I think you're right. Continue investigating.
控制器位置的线索一定在附近
The clue to the location of the control room must be around somewhere.
这里没有任何迹象表明这绝不是一颗行星
Nothing here would indicate that this is anything but a planet.
毫无疑问，但创造者会被认为是神
There's no question but the creators would have been considered gods.
这代表一颗恒星及其太阳系
This is a representation of a star and its solar system.
八颗，法布里尼太阳系中行星的数量
Eight planets, the number in the Fabrina solar system.
这些人是法布里尼人的后裔
These people are descendants of the Fabrini.
他们已经在这艘小行星船上生活了10,000年
They've been on this asteroid ship for 10,000 years.
[门打开]
[DOOR OPENS]
神谕：说吧
ORACLE: Speak.
- 是我，纳提拉  - 是的，纳提拉
- It is I, Natira. - Yes, Natira.
书上说只有人民的最高女祭司可以选择她的伴侣
It is written that only the high priestess of the people may select her mate.
是这么写的
It is so written.
我们中间的陌生人，三个访客
The strangers among us, the three visitors,
有一个叫麦考伊
there is one called McCoy.
我希望他留在这里
I wish him to remain here,
作为我的伴侣
as my mate.
他同意吗？
Does he agree to this?
我已经问过他了，他还没有给我他的答案
I have asked him. He has not yet given me his answer.
他必须成为人民中的一员，敬奉创造者
He must become one of the people, worship the creators,
并同意植入服从器
and agree to have the Instrument of Obedience.
他会被告知必须做什么
He will be told what must be done.
如果他同意所有的事情，那就可以
If he agrees to all things, it is permitted.
仔细教他我们的法律，这样他就不会亵渎
Teach him our laws carefully so he commits no sacrilege,
冒犯人民或创造者
no offense against the people or the creators.
我会的，哦，至高智慧
It will be done, oh, most wise.
- 入侵者是谁？  - 两个陌生人，柯克和史波克
- Who are the intruders? - Two strangers, Kirk and Spock.
- 麦考伊没有和他们在一起？  - 没有
- McCoy is not with them? - No.
他们犯了亵渎罪
They have committed sacrilege.
- 你知道必须做什么  - 我知道
- You know what must be done. - I know.
当神谕释放他们时，带他们走
When the Oracle releases them, take them.
蠢人，你以为我们是孩童？
Fools. You think we are children?
你认为你可以随心所欲
You think you can do as you please,
犯下任何让你开心的罪行？
commit whatever offense amuses you?
你要对我的朋友们做什么？
What are you going to do to my friends?
他们闯入了神谕室
They entered the Oracle room.
- 惩罚是死亡？  - 是的
- And the punishment is death? - Yes.
我不能做其他决定，我们相信他们，他们背叛了我们
I can make no other decision. We gave them our trust, they betrayed us.
- 他们是出于无知，纳提拉  - 他们说他们是出于友谊而来的
- They acted out of ignorance, Natira. - They said they came in friendship.
- 请让他们回到船上  - 我不能
- Please, let them return to the ship. - I cannot.
为了我？
For me?
我已经做出了决定
I've made my decision.
我会留在这，留在尤纳达
I'm staying here, on Yonada.
纳提拉
Natira.
无论他们做了什么，都是因为他们觉得他们必须做
They did what they did because they felt they had to.
请让他们回到船上，你不会后悔的
Please, let them return to the ship. You won't regret it.
你认为如果我为了幸福留下来，但我的朋友死了
How do you think I'd I feel if I stayed, with a chance to be happy,
我会有什么感觉？
but knowing my friends had died?
是的
Yes.
就这样吧，我将为麦考伊做这件事
So be it. This I will do for McCoy.
为了我们的幸福和未来
For our happiness and future.
你和我们一起回去？
You're returning with us?
不，我不回去
No, I'm not.
这不是一颗行星，而是一艘宇宙飞船，在与达兰五号发生碰撞的航向上
This isn't a planet, it's a spaceship, on a collision course with Daran V.
我自己也在毁灭的路上了
I'm on a kind of collision course myself.
我命令你和我们一起回去
I order you to return with us.
我拒绝
And I refuse.
如果我们不能校正这艘船的航向，我们就必须把它炸出太空
If we can't correct the course of this ship, we'll have to blast it out of space.
我打算和这些人呆在这艘船上，不管发生什么
I intend to stay on this ship with these people, whatever happens.
你的决定是不合逻辑的，医生
Your decision is most illogical, Doctor.
是吗，史波克先生？
Is it, Mr. Spock?
这是真的？
Is it really?
我和纳提拉在一起
I'm staying with Natira.
- 作为她的丈夫？  - 是的
- As her husband? - Yes.
吉姆，这样问是不是太过分了？
Is that too much to ask, Jim?
- 柯克呼叫企业号  - 我是斯科特
- Kirk to Enterprise. - Scott here.
我们要传送过去，锁定我们的信号
We're beaming over. Lock in on our signal.
传送史波克先生和我
Transport Mr. Spock and myself.
麦考伊医生呢？
What about Dr. McCoy?
他要留下来，斯科提，通话完毕
He's staying, Scotty. Kirk out.
神谕：成为尤纳达人民的一员
ORACLE: To be one of the people of Yonada,
服从器必须成为你肉体的一部分
the Instrument of Obedience must be made part of your flesh.
你现在同意吗？
Do you now give your consent?
- 我同意  - 开始
- I do. - Proceed.
有异议现在说，因为一旦完成，就不可改变
Say now. Because once done, it is done.
没有异议
Let it be done.
现在你成为我们中的一员了
You are now one with my people.
愿我给你你想要的爱
May I give you the love you want,
让你拥有美好的时光
and make the time you have beautiful.
- 我们现在有同样的思想  - 同一颗心
- We are now of one mind. - One heart.
同一个生命
One life.
完成了，哦，至高智慧
It is done, oh, most wise.
我们的生活与创造者相连
Our living link with the creators.
那么，教他作为人民必须知道的东西
Teach him, then, what he must know as one of the people.
这是人民之书
This is the Book of the People,
当我们到达诺言的新世界时才能阅读
to be read when we reach the new world of the promise.
这是创造者给予的
It was given by the creators.
人民知道它的内容吗？
Do the people know its contents?
只知道这里是我们的世界
Only that it tells of our world here
以及为什么我们必须尽快离开它到新世界
and why soon we must leave it for the new world.
人民必须离开这里的原因告诉你了吗？
Has the reason that the people must leave here been revealed to you?
不，它没有
No, it has not.
- 你不想知道它的秘密吗？  - 不
- Don't you long to know its secrets? - No.
对我来说，只要知道我们到家后会明白一切就足够了
It is enough for me to know we shall understand all when we reach home.
柯克：舰长日志，星历5476.4
KIRK: Captain's log, stardate 5476.4.
我们和尤纳达在一条平行的航线上
We are on a parallel course with Yonada.
它仍在与达兰五号发生碰撞的航向上
It is still on a collision course with Daran V.
由于我们未能校正它的航向，以及麦考伊医生的病
Our failure to correct its course, and Dr. McCoy's illness,
使得我们必须与星际舰队司令部联系
made contact with Starfleet Command imperative.
韦斯特弗利特：柯克舰长，我同意你留下的愿望
WESTERVLIET: Captain Kirk, I sympathize with your wish to stay.
但我希望你认识到继续你的使命的必要性
But I hope you recognize the need to continue your mission.
- 这就是问题所在，长官  - 可能我没说清楚
- That is the problem, sir. - Perhaps I haven't made myself clear.
让我重申一下
Let me restate it.
你已被免除对尤纳达的所有责任
You have been relieved of all responsibility for Yonada.
星际舰队司令部会处理这种情况
Starfleet Command will take care of the situation.
我相信是时候继续前进了
I believe it is time to move on.
是的，这些就是命令
Yes, those are the orders.
乌乎拉[通过对讲机]：柯克舰长，舰桥呼叫柯克舰长
UHURA [OVER INTERCOM]: Captain Kirk. Bridge to Captain Kirk.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
- 麦考伊医生的紧急呼叫，长官  - 接通
- An urgent call from Dr. McCoy, sir. - Put him on.
- 麦考伊：吉姆？  - 是我，老骨头
- McCOY: Jim? - Yes, Bones.
- 我们可以让他们回到正轨  - 你找到控制器了吗？
- We can get them back on course. - You found the controls?
没有，但我看过包含创造者知识的书
No, but I've seen the book that contains knowledge of the creators.
如果你…
And if you...
如果你能得到它…
If you can get to it...
史波克…
Spock...
- …挖掘信息  - 它在哪里？
- ...dig out the information. - Where is it?
[呐喊]
[SHOUTS]
老骨头，你没事吧？回答我！
Bones, are you all right? Answer me!
老骨头，是什么？
Bones, what is it?
麦考伊，怎么了？
McCoy, what's happening?
怎么了，麦考伊？
What's happening, McCoy?
你杀了你朋友
You are killers of your friend.
我要把你处死
I will have you put to death.
除非你死了，否则他不会服从
Until you are dead, he will disobey.
- 我要看着你死！- 照顾好麦考伊
- I will see you die! - Take care of McCoy.
他不是我们人民的一部分
He is not part of our people.
你已经解除了他服从的誓言
You've released him from his vow of obedience.
我们已经将他从你们的神谕的暴行中解放出来了
We have freed him from the cruelty of your Oracle.
[呻吟]
[GROANS]
麦考伊
McCoy.
老骨头
Bones.
你说了一些关于一本书的事情，它在哪里？
You said something about a book. Where is it?
一定不能让他们知道
They must not know.
…神谕室
The... Oracle room.
你们绝不能看这本书，这是亵渎
You will never see the book. It is sacrilege.
守卫！
Guards!
现在听我说，你必须听我要说的话
Now listen to me, you must listen to what I have to say.
给我一点时间和你说话
Give me one moment to speak to you.
就一会儿，纳提拉…
One moment. Natira...
如果你不相信我的话，就叫守卫
If you don't believe what I say, call the guards.
我们将接受您下达的任何惩罚
We'll accept any punishment you decree.
- 你想说什么？  - 你必须相信这是事实
- What do you wish to say? - You must believe it's the truth.
- 你们的真相，你们世界的真相  - 是的，我的世界和你的世界
- Your truth. Of your world. - Yes, my world and your world.
你不服从创造者，你怎么了解我们的世界？
You do not obey the creators. How can you understand my world?
我了解
I understand.
我了解，纳蒂拉
I understand, Natira.
10,000年前，一个太阳正在消亡，它的世界也随之消亡
10,000 years ago, a sun was dying and with it, its world.
正是你在神谕室的饰板上看到的世界
The world you see on the plaque in the Oracle room.
- 尤纳达是那个世界的一部分  - 不
- The world of which Yonada is a part. - No.
那是你们祖先的世界，你们的…创造者
It is the world of your ancestors, your... creators.
它不再存在
It no longer exists.
- 你疯了  - 不，我没有，听我说！
- You are mad. - No, I'm not. Listen to me!
听我说！
Hear me out!
当你们的祖先发现他们的世界即将消亡时
When your ancestors discovered their world was dying,
他们建造了一艘巨大的船并挑选了他们最优秀的人
they built a great ship and chose their best people.
他们希望自己的种族能够延续下去，他们将飞船送入太空
They wished for their race to survive. They sent the ship out into space.
你想让我相信尤纳达是一艘船吗？
You wish me to believe that Yonada is a ship?
是的
Yes.
但我们有太阳，它没有死，晚上，我能看到星星
But we have a sun. It did not die. At night I see the stars.
不
No.
你住在一个空心球里
You are living inside a hollow ball.
你们的祖先创造它，带你踏上旅程
Your ancestors created it to take you on a journey.
前往一颗充满希望的新星球
To a promised new planet.
为什么你们来到尤纳达我们才知道真相？
Why should the truth wait for you to come to Yonada?
控制器有缺陷，除非我们纠正它
A flaw developed in the controls, and unless we correct it,
尤纳达将杀死数百万人并摧毁一个它不知道的世界
Yonada will kill millions and destroy a world it doesn't know.
为什么要对我们隐瞒真相？
Why should the truth be kept from us?
为什么创造者要向我们隐瞒？
Why should the creators hide it from us?
不，不，你没有说实话
No. No, you do not speak the truth.
我相信只有神谕，我相信…
I believe only the Oracle. I believe...
让我们移除服从器
Let us remove the Instrument of Obedience,
就像我们为麦考伊所做的
the way we did for McCoy.
纳提拉…
Natira...
你觉得她相信我说的吗？
Do you think she understood me?
她有点相信，她没叫守卫
She understood something. There are no guards.
神谕：你听了非信徒的话
ORACLE: You have listened to the words of the non-believers.
是的，我听了
Yes, I have listened.
那是初犯，你感受到警告的痛苦了吗？
That was the first transgression. You felt the pain of warning?
- 是的，我感受了  - 你为什么还要听？
- Yes, I did. - Why did you listen further?
- 他们说他们说的是实话  - 他们的真相
- They said they spoke the truth. - Their truth.
- 真相不是所有人的真相吗？  - 尤纳达的真相就是你的真相
- Is truth not truth for all? - The truth of Yonada is your truth.
你不必知道别的，悔改你的不顺服
There can be no other for you. Repent your disobedience.
我必须知道世界的真相
I must know the truth of the world.
你的朋友告诉我你的世界
Your friends have told me of your world.
- 他们说的是实话  - 我相信你
- They spoke the truth. - I believe you.
我相信，创造者让我们处于黑暗之中
I believe. The creators kept us in darkness.
我无能为力
There's nothing I can do.
我相信你，丈夫
I believe with you, husband.
- 她还好吗？  - 她会好的，我会陪她
- Is she all right? - She will be. I'll stay with her.
那本书在石碑中
The book is in the monolith.
神谕：这是对圣殿的亵渎
ORACLE: It is sacrilege to the temple.
我们这样做是为了尤纳达人民的生存
We do this for the survival of the people of Yonada.
你们不相信，你们被禁止看这本书
You do not believe. You are forbidden to gaze at the book.
我们无意亵渎你的信仰，我们必须查阅这本书
We mean no desecration to your faith. We must consult the book.
这是亵渎，禁止这么做，惩罚是死
It is blasphemy. You are forbidden. The punishment is death.
[雷声]
[THUNDER CRACK]
温度111度并不断上升
Temperature 111 degrees and rising.
- 你怎么打开这个东西？  - 115度
- How do you open this thing? - 115 degrees.
同时按下左侧的三个下方行星
Press the three lower planets on the left hand side, simultaneously.
120度
120 degrees.
计划一定在那里面
The plan must be in there.
- 有索引吗？  - 是的
- Is it indexed? - Yes, it is.
快点，史波克
Hurry, Spock.
它指的是祭坛
It refers to the altar.
向中心施加压力，直到它打开
Apply pressure to the center until it opens.
- 让她摆脱炎热  - 我已经摧毁了加热元件
- Get her out of the heat. - I've neutralized the heating elements.
现在我们在这儿没事了
We'll be all right here, now.
神谕不能再惩罚我们了
The Oracle can no longer punish us.
- 你的朋友们阻止了它吗？  - 是的
- Your friends have prevented it? - Yes.
他们会让这个…船
And will they send this... ship,
再次前往创造者想去的地方？
again to the land the creators intended?
是的
Yes.
那很好
That is good.
可运行，与企业号没有太大区别
Functional. Not too different from the Enterprise.
八根管子里有一根似乎有问题
There seems to be a weakness in one of the eight tubes.
- 足以校正它的航线吗？  - 是的
- Enough to turn it off course? - Yes.
让我检查一下那个引擎
Let me check that engine.
史波克：一个非常简单的问题，很容易纠正
SPOCK: A very simple problem, easy to correct.
那就来吧
Then come.
- 不  - 不要害怕
- No. - Don't be afraid.
我不怕不服从的惩罚
I do not fear the punishment of disobedience.
- 那就来吧，我们得快点…  - 不，我不能和你一起去
- Then come, we must hurry... - No, I cannot go with you.
这不是恐惧
It is not fear.
我理解创造者的伟大目的
I understand the great purpose of the creators.
我会尊重它
I shall honor it.
你打算留在这里，在尤纳达？
You intend to stay here, on Yonada?
我会心甘情愿地留下来，因为那是我必须做的
I shall stay willingly, and because that is what I must do.
那我就不离开你了
Then I won't leave you.
麦考伊会留在这里等死吗？
Will McCoy stay here to die?
不，麦科伊不会在年富力强的时候放弃生命
No, McCoy will not let go of life in the fullness of years.
现在，我比以往任何时候都更想探索宇宙
Now, more than ever, I wish to search through the universe
为我自己和所有像我一样的人找到治愈方法
to find a cure for myself and all others like me.
我希望你和我在一起
And I want you to be with me.
这是我的宇宙
This is my universe.
你带着伟大的使命来到这里
You came here with a great mission,
拯救我的人民
to save my people.
我要放弃他们吗？
Shall I abandon them?
也许有一天，如果可能的话
Perhaps one day, if it is permitted,
你会再次找到尤纳达
you will find Yonada again.
我相信我们可以尝试校正航线
I believe we can attempt the course correction.
好的
Good.
回到标记的航向
Going back to marked headings.
制导控制接管
Guidance controls taking over.
我们可以让船回到自动状态
We can allow the ship to go back to automatic.
保持在红色标记的航线上
Steadying on course marked in red.
舰长
Captain.
信息档案
Intelligence files.
他们的库包含法布里尼的全部知识
Their banks contain the total knowledge of the Fabrini,
准备供人们在到达目的地时进行咨询
ready for the people to consult when they arrive at their destination.
而且他们似乎积累了大量的医学知识
And they seem to have amassed a great deal of medical knowledge.
太好了，医生，白细胞计数恢复正常
Excellent, Doctor. The white corpuscle count is back to normal.
你的血红蛋白计数正常
Your hemoglobin count is normal,
这表明流向每个细胞的氧气
which indicates that the flow of oxygen to each cell
恢复到其丰富的能量水平
is back up to its abundantly energetic level.
谢谢你，史波克先生，你带回了法布里尼的知识
Thank you, Mr. Spock, for bringing back the knowledge of the Fabrini.
法布里尼的后代计划在390天内
The Fabrini descendants are scheduled to disembark
登陆他们既定的行星
on their promised planet in 390 days.
想那个时候我们可以设法到达那附近
I think we could manage to be in that vicinity at that time.
如果你想亲自感谢法布里尼人的话
If you wanted to thank the Fabrini personally.